International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5276
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  Letter from Rockwell Kent, 5/5/49, re speaking engagement arrangements, and a short report of the Paris Congress which Rockwell attended; report on "Ridgefield" and "Our Home for the Aged"; and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  In Yiddish. 5/2/49 - complaints about Comrade Weinstein's management of Camp Kinderland and the old age home; and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1950 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  Routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  Letter from A. Bohlinger, New York State Department of Insurance, requesting all records on Saltzman's possession turned over to Bohlinger, 7/25/51.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  Correspondence re members' dues; correspondence with Insurance Department re lodge bank statements; letter re discrimination at New York University killing of Enus L. Christiani, certificate and assignment of Bail Fund of the Civil Rights Congress of New
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1953-1956 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  Re cultural tour, status of legal fight for the Order; from Los Angeles Office re "desperately in need of funds"; letter re Workmen's Circle, 1956.
- Saltzman, Rubin (Box 29, Folder 19)
- Saltzman, Rubin (Box 29, Folder 20)
  Form letter re fund raising for protection of the shules; "New Year's Greetings From Rubin Saltzman"; letter to President Truman; citation from the Council of Fraternal and Benevolent Organizations.
- Saltzman, Rubin - Speeches and Lectures (Box 63, Folder 8)
  In Yiddish. Re Children's Camps, schools as a war front, Warsaw Ghetto Uprising; manuscript and speech - "On History of the Fraternal Movement" and "The Forward and the IWO"; speech re liquidation of IWO; speech "What Constitutes a `Hazard'" re liquidation
- Fraternal History (Box 63, Folder 9)
- Sandler, G. - Executive Secretary, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  Correspondence and form letters re routine (meeting announcements, speaking engagements, etc.); includes, in Yiddish, statement and report of contribution and support of orphan homes in Biro-Bidgan and Poland programs.
- Sandler, G., 1946 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence with Zaltzman and Yukelson; branch affairs - constitutional issues, transfers, concert tours, camp.
- Sandler, G. - Executive Secretary, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Sandler, G., 1950-1952 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Sandler, G., 1953 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  Re reinstatement of members; tour agenda and expenses; arrangements of officers to visit all lodges to explain legal difficulties, keeping membership intact, etc.
- Starr, George - National Director and Director of English-Speaking Lodges, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  Routine correspondence.
- Starr, George - National Director, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  Form letters re support of Crusade to End Lynching; Million Dollar Drive; Jews in D. P. Camps and Palestine; and routine.
- Starr, George - National Director, 1944 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  Correspondence re organizing a lodge in Kingston, New York; letter from member in Hartford, Connecticut, asking about JPFO-owned cemeteries and Starr's reply; from lodge in Milwaukee re activities of the lodge; and routine.
- Starr, George - National Director, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  Substantial correspondence with Samuel S. Shapira who called himself "the father of the revival of the ideals of liberty, democracy and the Bill of Rights ... against growing fascism in America...."
- Starr, G., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Starr, G., 1948 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Starr, George - National Director, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  Correspondence with Mike Hecht re article in The Fraternalist about the wages of employees at the Ridgefield Resort.
- Starr, George - National Director - Tours, 1946-1947 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  Generally routine correspondence re arrangements, although some information about lodges in Houston, Texas, Florida, and California.
- Starr, George - National Director - Tours, 1946-1947 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Yukelson - Editor of the Tribune and Morgen Freiheit, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  Correspondence re printing articles and notices - all Yiddish.
- Zhitlovsky, Chaim - President, Committee of Jewish Writers and Artists in America, 1941-1943 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  Correspondence mainly with Saltzman re opposition to "Tanks for Russia" Campaign; lecture tour itineraries; press releases and telegrams concerning his death, letter from his family re publication of his manuscripts.
- Correspondence - General, 1944-1949 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  Routine re changes of addresses, requests for publications and information.
- Correspondence - Inter-Office Memos, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  Re meeting arrangements; recruitment; general activities; dues; reinstatements.
- Correspondence - Inter-Office Memos, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Inter-Office Memos, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Inter-Office Memos, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - General, 1938-1953 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  Routine. In Yiddish.
- Correspondence - Form Letters, 1945-1950 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  In Yiddish .To various IWO branches re Book news, relief appeal, anniversary of the Order, banquets, membership drives, tours, holidays, district conventions.
- Lodge 5 and 14, 1949-1955 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish - re help for Polish journey; not allowing a Communist to become a member of Lodge 14 in Scranton, Pennsylvania.
- Lodge 19, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  Yiddish - re $10,000 campaign to open a branch in Harlem.
- Lodge 20, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Yiddish - re setting up relief campaign of which 60% would be returned to collecting lodge.
- Lodge 24 and 26, 1945-1951 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  Yiddish - routine.
- Lodge 27, 1948-1950 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  Some Yiddish - local member resigns his membership because of IWO being placed on list as subversive organization; Sandler (Yiddish) - fund raising is the very survival of the organization.
- Lodge 31 and 34, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  Both Yiddish and English - routine.
- Lodge 37, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Lodge 45, 46 and 48, 1946-1953 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  English and Yiddish - routine
- Lodge 49 and 51, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  English and Yiddish - routine.
- Lodge 55, 57 and 61, 1945-1950 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  Yiddish routine.
- Lodge 62, 1947-1950 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  English - Atlanta, Georgia, Lodge - Correspondence re dues, correspondence re Henry Wald, member, re insurance premiums and coverage and his wife being involved in a loyalty board hearing - Wald says, "I am apparently affiliated with an inefficient and un
- Lodge 62, 1948-1950 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  Yiddish - re members resigning, attack on the Order, dissolving the lodge.
- Lodge 69, 71 and 77, 1948-1953 (Box 31, Folder 13)
- Lodge 90, 1948-1949 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  Yiddish and English - routine.
- Local 91, 92 and 93, 1947-1949 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  English and Yiddish - re problems in Ohio and lodge with Youngstown Jewish Community Relations Council demanding that JPFO be expelled as a member of the Council.
- Local 98, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  English and Yiddish - re dissolving Lodge 257 and members transferred to Lodge 98.
- Lodge 100 and 101, 1938-1953 (Box 31, Folder 17)
- Lodge 102, 103 and 104, 1945-1950 (Box 31, Folder 18)
- Lodge 105, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  Yiddish and English - routine re sick benefit claims and a resignation of a member.
- Lodge 106, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  English - re backing Saltzman and other leaders in the struggle to re-establish the rights and privileges of members.
- Lodge 111, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  English - reinstatement of a member.
- Lodge 112, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  Yiddish - re campaign to open branch in Harlem
- Lodge 113, 1938-1953 (Box 31, Folder 23)
- Lodge 115, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  Yiddish - routine
- Lodge 117 and 120, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  English and Yiddish (Lodge 117) re meeting in New Haven and routine.
- Lodge 122, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  English - re inquiry by Insurance Department as to financial statements of lodge.
- Lodge 124 and 126, 1944-1953 (Box 31, Folder 27)
- Lodge 128, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  English - routine
- Lodge 132, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 29)
- Lodge 36, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 30)
- Lodge 136, 1945-1953 (Box 31, Folder 31)
- Lodge 138, 1945-1953 (Box 31, Folder 32)
- Lodge 141 and 142, 1950-1953 (Box 31, Folder 33)
- Lodge 143, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 34)
- Lodge 148, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  English - routine.
- Lodge 149, 1944-1953 (Box 31, Folder 36)
- Lodge 153, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 37)
- Lodge 158 and 159, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 38)
- Lodge 160 (Box 31, Folder 39)
- Lodge 165, 1949-1946 (Box 31, Folder 40)
  English and Yiddish correspondence re low wages of kitchen help at Ridgefield Resort; scattered issues of Local newsletter.
- Lodge 167, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 41)
  Yiddish support letter and reply.
- Lodge 169, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 42)
- Lodge 170, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 43)
- Lodge 175, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 44)
- Lodge 176, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 45)
  English and Yiddish routine.
- Lodge 182, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 46)
- Lodge 184, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 47)
- Lodge 186, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 48)
- Lodge 187, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 49)
- Lodge 191, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 50)
- Lodge 192, 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 51)
  English - Miami, Florida re wanting to form a "General Lodge rather than JPFO Lodge; and routine.
- Lodge 192, 1945-1953 (Box 31, Folder 52)
- Lodge 196, 198 and 200, 1938-1952 (Box 64, Folder 8)
- Lodge 204, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 9)
- Lodge 206, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 10)
- Lodge 211, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 11)
- Lodge 215, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 12)
- Lodge 223 and 224, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 13)
- Lodge 228 and 230, 1945-1954 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  Yiddish and English - includes "General Report" in Yiddish; and routine.
- Lodge 232, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 15)
- Lodge 236, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 16)
- Lodge 247 and 250, 1938-1953 (Box 64, Folder 17)
- Lodge 251 and 256, 1949-1953 (Box 64, Folder 18)
- Lodge 257, 1947-1953 (Box 64, Folder 19)
- Lodge 258, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 20)
- Lodge 263 and 265, 1945-1953 (Box 64, Folder 21)
- Lodge 267, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 22)
- Lodge 273, 1953 (Box 64, Folder 23)
- Lodge 277, 1946-1953 (Box 64, Folder 24)
- Lodge 278 and 279, 1942-1953 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  Yiddish and English routine.
- Lodge 281, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Lodge 283, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Lodge 283, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Lodge 302 and 304, 1938-1939 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Lodge 337, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Lodge 358, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Lodge 400, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Lodge 419, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 9)
- Lodge 438, 1947-1953 (Box 32, Folder 10)
- Lodge 440, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 11)
- Lodge 443, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Lodge 448, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  English newsletter.
- Lodge 454, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Lodge 463, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  English - routine (members request to have names removed from all mailing lists).
- Lodge 464, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 16)
- Lodge 465, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 17)
- Lodge 466, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 18)
- Lodge 467, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 19)
- Lodge 469, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  English newsletter and correspondence re staffing problems in this Los Angeles lodge.
- Lodge 471, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  English newsletters.
- Lodge 477, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  English and Yiddish - re resolution against World War II and concentration camps.
- Lodge 482, 1945-1953 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  English - Washington, D.C. lodge, substantial amount of correspondence, mostly concerning routine lodge activities
- Lodge 484, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  English - member (Indiana) with post office position requested to have his name removed from mailing list because the FBI and Post Office Department Taken every name of person receiving Fraternal Outlook
- Lodge 486, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 25)
- Lodge 488, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  English correspondence with Jack Greenhill (President Lodge - Los Angeles) re his resignation due to the IWO splitting up into nationality groups which he called "discrimination".
- Lodge 489, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 27)
- Lodge 491, 1950-1953 (Box 32, Folder 28)
- Lodge 493, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 29)
- Lodge 498, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  English - one issue of newsletter.
- Lodge 498, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 31)
- Lodge 508, 1948-1953 (Box 32, Folder 32)
- Lodge 514, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 33)
- Lodge 517, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  English newsletter and routine.
- Lodge 521, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  English correspondence re Ridgefield Resort (a JPFO Institution) being too expensive for the "average worker".
- Lodge 523, 1945-1950 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  English correspondence re the Jewish Community Center in Poughkeepsie, New York, denied use of Center to JPFO.
- Lodge 540, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 37)
- Lodge 543, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 38)
- Lodge 562, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 39)
- Lodge 580, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 40)
- Lodge 585, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 41)
- Lodge 600, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 42)
- Lodge 607, 1952-1953 (Box 32, Folder 43)
- Lodge 658, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 44)
- Lodge 620, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 45)
- Lodge 660, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 46)
- Lodge 704, 1946-1953 (Box 32, Folder 47)
- Lodge 746, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 48)
- Lodge 751, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 49)
- Lodge 760, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 50)
- Lodge 795, 1944-1948 (Box 32, Folder 51)
  English - 1 issue of newsletter and routine.
- Lodge 803, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 52)
- Lodge 805, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 53)
- Lodge 807, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 54)
- Lodge 817, 1947-1953 (Box 32, Folder 55)
  English - routine and newsletters.
- Lodge 818, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 56)
- Lodge 828, 1944-1950 (Box 32, Folder 57)
- Lodge 860, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 58)
- Lodge 905 and 926, 1945-1953 (Box 32, Folder 59)
- Lodge 953, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 60)
- Lodge 3292, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 61)
- Lodge 4507, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 62)
- Chicago Lodge, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 63)
  English broadside re Chanukah Party.
- Los Angeles District, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 64)
  English resolution to Governor Thomas Dewey re liquidation
- Manhattan District (Box 32, Folder 65)
  2 page manuscript "The Fight Against Racist Poison in the Manhattan District, JPFO"; 2 page manuscript "An Act of White Chauvinism."
- Philadelphia District, 1944-1947 (Box 32, Folder 66)
  7 page "Minutes - Philadelphia Cultural Conference - JPFO, October 27, 1946"; scattered issues of newsletter; clippings; correspondence re 15th Anniversary Celebration in Philadelphia; correspondence between Sol Rotenberg, Executive Director, and John B.
- Locals - Miscellaneous, 1948-1951 (Box 64, Folder 25)
  Routine correspondence re some California lodges; Volume 1, Number 1, issue of The Spark (January 1948).
- Locals - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 26)
  Completed forms by lodge number, "Report to General Office on Election of Officers" giving elected officers' names and addresses, location of lodge and replies to questions such as: address of meeting place, frequency of meetings, medical service available
- Locals - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 27)
- Locals - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 28)
- Locals - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 29)
- Akron, Ohio - Mon., Feb. 4th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Albany, NY - Mon., Jan. 28th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Albany, NY - Friday, April 24th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Atlantic City - Wednesday, Jan. 16th, Monday, Jan. 21 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Baltimore, MD - 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Boston, MA - Friday, Jan. 11th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 6)
- Bridgeport, CT - Thursday, Jan. 24th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 7)
- Brighton, NY - Saturday, Jan. 12, Saturday, Jan. 26 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 8)
- Bronx, NY - Saturday, Jan. 17 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Brooklyn, NY - Saturday, March 21st, Saturday, April 4th (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 10)
- Buffalo, NY - Thursday, Jan. 31st, Friday, February 1st (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 11)
- Buffalo, NY - Tuesday, April 21st, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 12)
- Chicago, Ill. - Saturday, April 18, Sunday, April 19, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 13)
- Chicago, Ill - Saturday, Feb. 9, Sunday, Feb. 10, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 14)
- Cincinnati, OH - Thursday, Feb. 7 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 15)
- Cleveland, OH - Thursday, Feb. 7, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 16)
- Cleveland, OH - Wednesday, April 15, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 17)
- Detroit, MI - Sunday, Feb. 3, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 18)
- Detroit, MI - Sunday, April 12, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 19)
- East Brooklyn Lodges, JPFO - Saturday, Jan. 26, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 20)
- Fall River, MA - Wednesday, Jan. 9 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 21)
- Far Rockaway, NY - Sunday, Jan. 6, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 22)
- Hartford, CT - Jan. 6 or Jan. 11 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 23)
- Hartford, CT - Thursday, April 30, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 24)
- Jamaica, Queens - Friday, April 3, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 25)
- Lakewood, NJ - Monday, Jan. 21 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 26)
- Los Angeles, CA - Saturday, Feb. 16, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 27)
- Manhattan, NY - Saturday, March 28, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 28)
- Miami, FL - Sunday, February 24, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 29)
- Milwaukee, WI - Monday, Feb. 10, 1951 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 30)
- Milwaukee, WI - Friday, April 17 or Monday, April 20, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 31)
- Minneapolis, MN - Sunday, Feb. 3, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 32)
- Minneapolis, MN - Tuesday, April 21, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 33)
- Monticello, NY - Wednesday, Jan. 23, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 34)
- Montreal, Canada - Jan. 9 or Jan. 31 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 35)
- New Haven, CT - Friday, March 20, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 36)
- Newark, NJ - Sunday, March 29, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 37)
- Newark, NJ - Tuesday, February 26 or Thursday, February 28 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 38)
- Norfolk, VA - Tues., Jan. 15 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 39)
- Passaic - Temporary - Wednesday, Jan. 23 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 40)
- Passaic, NJ - Wednesday, April 8, 1955 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 41)
- Patterson, NJ - Sunday, Jan. 27, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 42)
- Patterson, NJ - Sunday, April 26, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 43)
- Petaluma, CA - Monday, Feb. 18, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 44)
- Philadelphia, PA - Saturday, April 4, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 45)
- Phoenix, AZ - Thursday, Feb. 21 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 46)
- Pittsburgh, PA - Tuesday, Feb. 5, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 47)
- Pittsburgh, PA - Friday, April 10, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 48)
- Poughkeepsie, NY - Mon., April 27, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 49)
- Providence, RI - Thursday, Jan. 10, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 50)
- Far Rockaway, NY - Sunday, March 22, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 51)
- Rochester, NY - Wednesday, Jan. 30th, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 52)
- Rochester, NY - Friday, April 24, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 53)
- St. Paul, MN - Wednesday, April 15, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 54)
- St. Paul, MN - Wednesday, February 13, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 55)
- San Francisco, CA - Sunday, Feb. 17, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 56)
- Springfield, MA - Tuesday, Jan. 8, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 57)
- Springfield, MA - Wednesday, March 25, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 33, Folder 58)
- Stanford, MA - Wednesday, Jan. 23, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 1)
- Syracuse, NY - Tuesday, Jan. 29, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 2)
- Syracuse, NY - Thursday, April 23, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 3)
- Toms River, NJ - Wednesday, Jan. 16, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 4)
- Toms River, NJ - Tuesday, March 25, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 5)
- Toronto, Canada - Saturday, Feb. 2, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 6)
- Tucson, AZ - Wednesday, Feb. 20, 1952 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 7)
- Washington, DC - Sunday, May 3, 1953 (Yiddish Correspondence) (Box 65, Folder 8)
- CT - Scripts (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Concert Schedules, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- CT - Questionnaire Letter (Box 34, Folder 3)
- 1952 Concert Series Accounting (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Concert Tour, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 5)
- Tour Receipts (Box 34, Folder 6)
- Concert Tour Expenses (Box 34, Folder 7)
- Concert Tour Leaflet Proofs (Box 34, Folder 8)
- Concert Tour Pending (Box 34, Folder 9)
- Concert Tour, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 10)
- Leaflet - 1953 Concert Tour (Box 34, Folder 11)
- First Letter CT, 1953 (Box 34, Folder 12)
- English Speech (Box 34, Folder 13)
- Yiddish Speech - CT (Box 34, Folder 14)
- Educational Activities, 1944-1949 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  Includes draft of "Plan for Cultural Work in the English Speaking Lodges"; "Jews in American Democratic Movements" by Morris U. Schappes, 13 pages, 1949; "Warsaw Ghetto Program, Activities Manual No. 1," 7 pages, 1946; "The Jews in the Post-War World," out
- Jefferson Players, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  News release; photographs; form letter; programs; routine correspondence; history of Jefferson Players and constitution; rates for bookings.
- Jewish History Week, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  Speech; episode in the story of Jews in America; recommended bibliography for Story Week (in Yiddish).
- Miscellaneous, 1943-1951 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  Routine correspondence; proposed program services for Peoples Radio Foundation, Inc.; Cultural Fund ledger sheets; form letters; cultural bulletin; recommendations for Culture Panel Conference.
- Miscellaneous, 1943-1951 (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Music, 1946-1947 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  Includes sheet music; routine correspondence; a corrected copy of "Program Material for the Jewish Folk Song" by Ruth Rubin, 13 pages; leaflets; tickets; etc.
- Music, 1949-1952 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  Contents include pamphlet "Sing, America"; news release; routine correspondence; outline for music series; leaflets; memo; souvenir journal of Jewish People's Chorus of Washington Heights.
- National Jewish Youth Conference, 1950-1953 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  Includes proposed constitution and by-laws of the NJYC, 8 pages, 1950; "Dispel the Climate of Fear - Save the NJYC," 27 pages, 1953
- National Jewish Youth Conference, 1949-1951 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  Includes standing committee reports; special committee reports; outline of "Program of `Adoption' of Recently Established Agricultural Settlements by Youth Organizations Overseas" for presentation at assembly, 2 pages, 1950; special committee report on Re
- National Jewish Youth Conference, 1950-1952 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  Includes form letters, post cards.
- National Jewish Youth Conference, 1950-1952 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  Includes a call to the annual conference, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlet, newspapers.
- Other, 1947-1955 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  News release "Opening of ORT School in Havana", and miscellaneous.